#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/osama-ahmed-khan-789a1626 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Microsoft Office Troubleshooting Management

## Languages

Urdu (Professional Working)
English (Limited Working)

#### Certifications

E-Commerce Management
Oracle 6i
Pl/Sql

Digital Competition in Financial Services

# Osama Ahmed Khan

Assistant Application Consultant at Euronet Pakistan (Private) Limited

Pakistan

# Summary

Experienced Information Technology Executive with a demonstrated history of working in the marketing and advertising industry. Skilled in Microsoft Word, Databases, English, Management, and Software Documentation. Strong information technology professional with a BSCS focused in Computer Science from Virtual University of Pakistan.

# Experience

Euronet Pakistan (Private) Limited Assistant Application Consultant April 2021 - Present (1 year) Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

MCB Bank Limited
Product Officer E-Commerce IPG Acquiring
April 2019 - April 2021 (2 years 1 month)
Karachi, Pakistan

E-Commerce IPG & POS Acquiring | Card Acquiring | Digital Banking | IT Group at MCB Bank Limited

- \*MasterCard (MIGS & MPGS) Payment Gateway Implementation.
- \* Create Merchant roles and rights as per profile.
- \* Prepare and analyze Business financial summary reports for management presentations, business reviews, key findings, and recommendations.
- \* Develop customized Process Flows of respective internal business requirement documentations.
- \* UAT/Testing all E-Commerce related projects
- \* Manage all existing merchants in all regions and onboarding of new merchant.
- \* Handle & Analysis Merchant Daily, Monthly & Yearly MIS numbers crunching and reporting.

- \* Develop and implement different strategies to ensure the stabilization of the product.
- \* Co-ordination for all product relevant activities between Merchant, Business Development, and the Technical Teams.
- \* Handle merchant emails to interact with internal department to resolve critical reporting,

Chargeback, and Settlement issues.

#### **HBL** - Habib Bank Limited

Support Officer (Branchless Banking Operations & ADC Operations)
January 2018 - April 2019 (1 year 4 months)

Karachi, Pakistan

Branchless Banking Operations Responsibility:

- \* Responsible for nationwide Konnect/HBL Express backed operations including customer complaint handling, agent/merchant/account open in all level registrations, corporate relations and product development.
- \* Conducting User Acceptance Testing (UAT) for new tools and processes.
- \* Co-ordination for all product relevant activities between Customer, Business Development, and the Technical Teams.
- \* Coordinate with IT & Vendor to resolve the issuing customer facing.
- \* Extract Data Check, ECIB & NADRA Verisys.
- \* Inputting of ANM (Agent network manager) & L0, L1, L2 Registration. Edit Agent Data, Account Closure, Guest Account Registration, and Upload ANM Name Scanning Files within TAT time. Block and Unblock Agent's Account in BB-BACK Office.
- \* Extract Files in BB-Back Office & HBPS to Prepare EOD, reconciliations and Check list In Excel.

#### ADC Operations Responsibility:

- \* Scrutiny and processing of Internet Banking [FCDB, Payment Portal] Customers Registration Forms.
- \* Return of discrepant Internet banking Forms/maintenance requests to respective branches with guidance [Memo or Email] for ensuring the completeness.
- \* To entertain customer maintenance [change in demographics, Inactivate Id, Block Id, Add users accounts, modify users' permission etc.] and confirm to respective internal and external stakeholders.

- \* Customer services by extending guidance and coordinating with IT for bridging resolution to the reported issues.
- \* Check and update Internet Banking Portal status and its onward submission to internal guarters.
- \* Prepare of all Successful & Unsuccessful Financial & non-Financial transactions (Cheque Book Request & Funds Transfer) made by Individual Customers & Non-Individual Customers.
- \* Preparation & transmission of Financial/Non-Financial statistics of Internet Banking / Mobile Banking to Senior Management on fortnightly basis for onwards reporting to internal stakeholders.

# Together Strategic & Business Consultants I.T Executive

June 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 8 months)

Business Centre, Shahrah-e-Faisal

- \* Window Server 2012 Manage, Group Policies, Delegation, Users Management.
- \* Maintain Data & Data Analysis.
- \* Create, Design & Maintain Websites.
- \* Computer networks and network installation
- \* E-mail Configurations and Internet Configurations.
- \* Installation of Windows, Printers, Scanners & Call Recording Devices.
- \* Resolve internet problems in all offices including HO
- \* Purchase equipment and I.T Inventory Update
- \* Preparing maintenance I.T report
- \* Ability to install and administer computer Hardware, Software, Networks & Security.
- \* Team building skills, Decision making skills, Analytical and problem solving skills.

# Education

Iqra University (Official)

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Management Information Systems (MIS) · (2020 - 2022)

Virtual University of Pakistan

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (January 2014 - January 2018)